export const chapter = "Chapter - 9: Air and Water ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "What is the primary cause of wind, as mentioned in the text?",
          optionA: "The rotation of the Earth",
          optionB: "The movement of clouds",
          optionC: "The heat of the sun",
          correctAnswer: "The heat of the sun",
        },
        {
          question: "What percentage of air is composed of oxygen?",
          optionA: "21%",
          optionB: "78%",
          optionC: "1%",
          correctAnswer: "21%",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Why is oxygen essential for animals, according to the text?",
          optionA: "It is needed for burning",
          optionB: "It is used by plants to make food",
          optionC: "It is required for breathing",
          correctAnswer: "It is required for breathing",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the role of air in maintaining temperature on land during summers?",
          optionA: "Air heats up the ocean surface",
          optionB:
            "Air minimizes the rise in temperature by moving cold air from the sea surface to the soil surface",
          optionC: "Air causes rapid temperature rise on the Earth's surface",
          correctAnswer:
            "Air minimizes the rise in temperature by moving cold air from the sea surface to the soil surface",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How does air contribute to the phenomenon of flight, as explained in the text?",
          optionA: "Air provides lift by reducing pressure",
          optionB: "Air creates turbulence",
          optionC: "Air increases gravitational force",
          correctAnswer: "Air provides lift by reducing pressure",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the primary way air helps in drying, as mentioned in the text?",
          optionA: "Air absorbs moisture",
          optionB: "Air conducts heat",
          optionC: "Air carries away water particles",
          correctAnswer: "Air carries away water particles",
        },
        {
          question:
            "In what state does water exist as ice, according to the text?",
          optionA: "Gas",
          optionB: "Solid",
          optionC: "Liquid",
          correctAnswer: "Solid",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is responsible for bringing back fresh water to the Earth, according to the text?",
          optionA: "Accumulation",
          optionB: "Condensation",
          optionC: "Precipitation",
          correctAnswer: "Precipitation",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the constant process that involves the transformation of water between different states, as described in the text?",
          optionA: "Water purification",
          optionB: "Water recycling",
          optionC: "Water condensation",
          correctAnswer: "Water recycling",
        },
        {
          question: "Why is the water cycle important, according to the text?",
          optionA: "To prevent floods",
          optionB: "To regulate Earth's temperature",
          optionC: "To ensure a constant supply of fresh water",
          correctAnswer: "To ensure a constant supply of fresh water",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "Every empty space is filled with a mixture of gases, called ____________.",
          optionA: "Wind",
          optionB: "Air",
          optionC: "Atmosphere",
          correctAnswer: "Air",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Air contains 78% ____________, 21% of ____________, and 1% is contributed by other gases, including carbon dioxide.",
          optionA: "Oxygen, Nitrogen",
          optionB: "Nitrogen, Oxygen",
          optionC: "Carbon dioxide, Oxygen",
          correctAnswer: "Nitrogen, Oxygen",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Oxygen is needed by animals to breathe. It is also needed for ____________.",
          optionA: "Burning",
          optionB: "Photosynthesis",
          optionC: "Respiration",
          correctAnswer: "Burning",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Air helps in flight: When a bird flaps its wings, air moves faster over its wings and body. This reduces the surrounding air pressure and lifts the bird higher into the ____________.",
          optionA: "Clouds",
          optionB: "Sky",
          optionC: "Atmosphere",
          correctAnswer: "Sky",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Air Maintains Temperature on the Land: During summers, air minimizes the rise in temperature by moving cold air from the ____________ surface.",
          optionA: "Soil",
          optionB: "Ocean",
          optionC: "Desert",
          correctAnswer: "Ocean",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Water is one of the most precious resources on earth and is necessary for all ____________.",
          optionA: "Animals",
          optionB: "Plants",
          optionC: "Living beings",
          correctAnswer: "Living beings",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Water is present in all three states of matter in nature â€“ as solid (__________) on mountains, as liquid (water) in rivers, seas, oceans, etc., and as gas (water vapour) in ____________.",
          optionA: "Snow, Air",
          optionB: "Ice, Air",
          optionC: "Liquid, Clouds",
          correctAnswer: "Ice, Air",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The total amount of water on Earth is relatively unchanging, and it has remained about the same since our planet's formation. The water is constantly undergoing the process of ____________, condensation, precipitation, and accumulation.",
          optionA: "Melting",
          optionB: "Evaporation",
          optionC: "Sublimation",
          correctAnswer: "Evaporation",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Evaporation: Heat of the sun causes evaporation of water from rivers, lakes, and oceans. The water vapour formed rises and mixes up with ____________.",
          optionA: "Clouds",
          optionB: "Air",
          optionC: "Water droplets",
          correctAnswer: "Air",
        },
        {
          question:
            "We use water for drinking and for other purposes. If the water did not come back to us through the water cycle, then we would not have ____________.",
          optionA: "Saltwater",
          optionB: "Fresh water",
          optionC: "Underground water",
          correctAnswer: "Fresh water",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "Air contains 78% oxygen, 21% nitrogen, and 1% other gases including carbon dioxide.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The heat of the sun causes evaporation of water, leading to the formation of water vapour.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Oxygen is only used by animals for breathing and has no other significant functions.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The Queen's Necklace in Mumbai is famous for its jewelry stores.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Water can exist in all three states of matter: solid, liquid, and gas.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The water cycle involves processes such as evaporation, condensation, precipitation, and accumulation.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question: "Mumbai is known as the political capital of India.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Air helps in normalizing temperature by melting ice and heating metals.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question: "Wind is not a conducting medium for sound.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The Chhatrapati Shivaji International Airport is located in Delhi.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
